NYSUT Legislative Department Files. 6174/005
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Higher Education Lobby Day, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  March 25-26, 1996. Analysis of key findings from the 1990 census: Demographic Trends in the NY-NJ Metropolitan Region: Educational Attainment and Economic Opportunity; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; tip sheet on effective lobbying; print ads/flyers on impact of state income tax cuts on local taxes and education; related testimony by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers
- Higher Education Lobby Day, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  March 11-12, 1996. Analysis of key findings from the 1990 census: Demographic Trends in the NY-NJ Metropolitan Region: Educational Attainment and Economic Opportunity; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; related testimony at state legislative committee hearings by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers
- Higher Education Lobby Day, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  February 27-28, 1995. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; briefing paper, "Truth and Consequences-What the Executive Budget Doesn't Tell You about CUNY and SUNY!"; related testimony at state legislative committee hearings by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers
- Higher Education Lobby Day, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  February 14-15, 1994. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; print ads/flyers; NYSUT Higher Education Budget Restoration Recommendations 1994-95: SUNY, CUNY, Community Colleges; related testimony to state legislative committee hearings by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers
- Higher Education Lobby Day, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  March 9-10, 1992. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; print ads/flyers; NYSUT Higher Education Budget Restoration Recommendations 1994-95: SUNY, CUNY, Community Colleges; report by American Economics Group, Inc., for NYSUT, "New York's 16 Billion Dilemma"; related testimony to state legislative committees by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers
- Higher Education Lobby Day, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  March 9-10, 1992. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; briefing book, "SUNY, CUNY, and the Community Colleges: State Aid, 1992-93"; print ad/flyer against cuts to public colleges; NYSUT press release, "Statewide Survey: Increase Support for Public Education"; Fact Finders, Inc., survey results, "NYSUT Tracking of Public Attitudes Toward Education," February 20, 1992; related testimony to state legislative committees by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers
- FNHP (Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals) Lobby Day, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  March 14, 1995. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of health, education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; newspaper clipping/flyer re Long-Term Home Health Care Program
- FNHP Lobby Day, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  March 10, 1993. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of health, social services, insurance, and finance committees; briefing book, "Health Care State Aid 1993-94"; text of legislation; report by American Economics Group, Inc., prepared for NYSUT, "New York's 16 Billion Dollar Dilemma"
- FNHP Lobby Day, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  March 4-5, 1991. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of health and finance committees; list of new legislators; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; briefing book, "Health Care State Aid 1991-92"; tip sheet on effective lobbying; print ads/flyers re state budget deficit, including copies of editorials; draft Comprehensive Report: Legislation of Interest to Higher Education and Health Care Professionals 1990
- Federal Legislative Reception, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart and executive vice president Herb Magidson to NY congressional delegation re legislative concerns; AFT and NYSUT briefing book endorsing comprehensive health care reform, supplemental appropriations; AFT newsletter, "On the Hill," with article, "AFT Supports Clinton Economic Plan," March 1993
- Political Action Committee (PAC), 1996 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  August 13, 1996. Political Action Committee report form; booklet, "Speak Out for Teachers: A compilation of responses to teacher bashing provided by the participants at NYSUT's 1996 Local Presidents' Conference"; flyer, "Letters to the Editor: Six Tips for Getting Published"
- Workshop Session III Delegate Selection Process 1995 Presidential Primaries (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Memo to PAC coordinators re national delegate selection process; instructions on selection process for Democratic and Republican primaries; instructions for circulating and filing petitions
- Presidents' Conference, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  August 1994. Agenda for Presidents' Conference on Endorsements; Guidelines for Political Endorsements for NYSUT; NYSUT Endorsement Recommendations for statewide offices, NYS Senate, Assembly, U.S. Congress; description of bills used for voting records, Senate-Assembly, U.S. Congress and Senate; congressional background information; congressional voting record 1993-94; Senate background information; NYS Senate voting record, 1993 and 1994; Assembly voting record, 1993 and 1994; Assembly background information; Assembly election results
- ED 12 Retirees, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  April 24, 1996. NYSUT's Bill to Extend the Moratorium on the Diminution of Retirees' Health Insurance; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of finance, education, and civil service committees
- Retiree Lobbying Training, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  April 25-26, 1994. Agenda for retiree lobbyist training; Rogers' Pocket Directory of members of Congress, NYS Senate, and Assembly, 1994; list of members of Senate and Assembly; issues briefing sheets re retiree health insurance, pension supplementation, permanent COLA legislation; tip sheet for effective lobbying
- Retiree Lobby Day, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  May 17, 1994. Briefing book on key NYSUT pension retirement bills; tip sheet on effective lobbying; memo to lobbyists
- Retiree Lobby Day, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Briefing book re permanent COLA, retirees' health insurance, election of retiree member of Retirement Board; print ad/flyer, "Why are we punishing our retired teachers?" (re need for permanent cost of living increase); list of legislators from North Country districts; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; memo to lobbyists
- Governor's Advisory Council, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Agenda for meeting of Advisory Council for a New New York, October 27, 1997; list of members; notes from meeting; memo recapping meeting, plan for report to governor, focus on education in State of the State address; description of organizations participating in Advisory Council; confidential outline, "Improving the Effectiveness of the Information Infrastructure in New York State Education," project kickoff, November 12
- Vacation Schedule, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Memos
- Agency Fee, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  List of estimated percentages of NYSUT employee time devoted to political activities not related to terms and conditions of teacher employment; definition of "chargeable" and "nonchargeable" activities subject to potential objection by union agency fee (dues) payers; related memo
- Luncheon- Matt Scott, Swan Club, Glen Head Landing, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  September 30, 1997. Memos re Alan Lubin's inability to attend event
- Luncheon ED 5-6 Canandaigua Yacht Club, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  October 1, 1997. Retiree Council Election District i5 newsletter re luncheon
- National Conference of State Legislatures, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  August 6-9, 1997. Memos re attendance and cancellation
- NYC Republican Senators Dinner, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  February 26, 1997. Letters to Republican state Senators representing NYC districts re cancellation of dinner in light of majority declining NYSUT invitation; letters of invitation
- Weinstein Dinner, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  January 27, 1997. Invitation and confirmation of dinner with Assembly members
- AFL-CIO Workers Compensation Meeting, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  1/24-26/1997. Memo from NYS AFL-CIO president Ed Cleary re meeting to plan legislative initiative to strengthen workers compensation
- AFT Special Conference on Vouchers, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  January 8-10, 1997. Memo; facilitative correspondence
- AFT Northeast Regional Conference, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  5/15-17, 1997. Agenda; facilitative correspondence
- New Yorkers for Fiscal Fairness, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  May 22, 1997. Registration form for New Yorkers for Fiscal Fairness roundtable discussion sessions on corporate welfare reform and the 1997 constitutional convention question; memo and agenda
- AFL-CIO Legislative Day, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  May 28, 1997. Conference call for annual legislative conference
- Community College Luncheon-Fort Orange Club, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  December 9, 1994. List of attendees from NYSUT and SUNY; list of NYSUT-affiliated community college presidents; letters of invitation to community college presidents; memo to college presidents re discussion topics
- Teacher Center Lobby Day, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  3/15/1994. Memo re teacher center policy board meeting and lobbying day
- SUNY-UUP Dinner-Fort Orange Club, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  September 9. Notes
- FNHP Lobby Day, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  May 24, 1994. Memo re Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Steering Committee seminar and lobbying day; memo re possible effort to amend Nurse Practices Act by State Education Department
- Special Act Schools-Fort Orange Club, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  July 6, 1994. Memo re informational seminar for Special Act school presidents re new reimbursement rates set by State Education Department
- Committee of 100, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  3/21-22, 1994. List of attendees; notice of meeting in preparation for lobby day; facilitative correspondence
- Cuomo-Record on Education, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  Bullet points on Gov. Mario Cuomo's record on education; list of education accomplishments; bullet points, the Cuomo Labor Record; comparison of Cuomo and Pataki record on taxes and support for education
- 1994 Election (Box 2, Folder 43)
  List of endorsed candidates for statewide office and by Senate and Assembly districts; memo to regional staff directors re phone banks (calls by groups of volunteers to voters on behalf of candidates), with attached tally sheets and scripts; agreement between NYSUT and NYS Democratic Committee for lease of computer equipment
- Local Presidents' Endorsement Conference, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  Tentative agenda, list of attendees, and related correspondence for Local Presidents' Conference on Endorsements
- VOTE/COPE Regional Campaign Coordinators, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  List of candidates endorsed at the NYSUT Presidents' Conference on Endorsements; press release; list of voting records of state legislators on bills of interest to NYSUT
- Presidents' Conference on Endorsements, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  Agenda; AFT On the Hill newsletter re preliminary voting record of 103rd Congress; list of conference attendees; list of conference attendees from UUP; list of Democratic Assembly candidates; list of Republican Senate candidates; Assembly primary list; Senate voting record on NYSUT key bills; list of candidates in legislative races from the mid-Hudson region; preliminary legislative report, 1994 session: major NYSUT program and support bills
- Budget-End of Session Food Orders, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  Facilitative correspondence
- NYSUT Endorsements, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  AFT On the Hill newsletter re preliminary voting record of 103rd Congress; lists of NYSUT endorsement recommendations for U.S. Congress, NYS Senate, Assembly, and statewide officers (governor, etc.); endorsements authorized by NYSUT Board of Directors
- Committee of 100, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  5/9-10, 1994. List of participants; facilitative correspondence
- NYSUT Endorsement Recommendations, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  NYSUT endorsement recommendations for U.S. Congress, NYS Senate, Assembly, governor and other statewide offices; list of endorsements authorized by NYSUT Board of Directors; NYSUT press release, "NYSUT Endorses [Gov. Mario] Cuomo for Re-Election"
- UFT Spring Education Conference, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  May 7, 1994 NY Hilton. Agenda; letter of invitation from United Federation of Teachers president Sandra Feldman to NYSUT director of legislation Ray Skuse
- UUP Friend of SUNY, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  5/6/1994. Invitation to award ceremony; list of invited guests; clipping from Chronicle of Higher Education re award recipient Ernest L. Boyer, president of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching
- Ad Hoc Task Force on School Violence, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  5/13/1994. Meeting agenda; resolutions on school violence; New Paltz High School Student Bill of Rights and Responsibilities: Behavior Code
- Higher Education Lobby Day, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  2/14-15, 1994. Lists of participants; facilitative correspondence
- Legislative Reception, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  1/31/1994. Invitations; facilitative correspondence
- Federal Legislative Reception, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  April 20, 1994. Invitations; facilitative correspondence
- Federal Legislative Reception Manny's (Kafka) Material, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Emanuel Kafka's (VOTE/COPE) materials; invitations; lists of attendees; legislative fact sheets
- Health Benefits Conference, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  June 3, 1993. Agenda; program brochure for New York State Public Sector Coalition on Health Benefits 7th Annual Conference, "The Health Care System in America-Do We Have the Courage to Change?"; letter of invitation to Ray Skuse; description of workshop on retiree health coverage
- Campaigns and Elections Seminars, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  6/11-13, 1993. Washington DC. Memo to Ray Skuse from John Costello reporting on campaigns and elections seminars, with suggestions for NYSUT
- Special Act Schools, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Letter re new law aimed at alleviating cash flow problem at Special Act schools, with attached text of legislation; list of NYSUT locals at Special Act schools
- Chapter 437 Omnibus Retirement Bill, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Outline of amended sections
- Pat's (Ballard) Retirement Dinner Fort Orange Club, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  List of invited members of Senate and Assembly, governor's office; invitation; notes
- Legislative Reception, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  February 1, 1993. Printed invitation; letters of invitation to union officials, community college presidents, and others; list of invitees; facilitative correspondence
- Federal Legislative Reception, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  March 23, 1993. Printed invitation; list of invitees; issues briefing book, AFT and NYSUT Support supplemental appropriations, reauthorization of funding, comprehensive health care reform package; AFT newsletter, On the Hill, "AFT Supports Clinton Economic Plan"; facilitative correspondence
- Committee of 100, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  February 22-23, 1993. Tentative agenda for lobbying day and notice of pre-lobby meeting, with issues briefing; letter to legislators from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson; list of participants; testimony by union officials at state legislative committee hearings; summary of executive budget re SUNY, CUNY, and community colleges; facilitative correspondence
- Committee of 100, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  5/17-18, 1993. Tentative agenda; list of participants; list of retirees from Retiree E.D. Councils 1-39; revised list of UFT participants; briefing book re pension, retirement, and labor issues; list of Senate and Assembly education committee members; facilitative correspondence
- New Local Presidents' Conference, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Program; description of NYSUT Legislative Department; descriptive flyer re VOTE/COPE and Legislative Department activities; completed evaluation forms; notes from conference planning meeting; document, NYSUT's Major Legislative Program and Support Bills: Passed both Houses and Signed into Law as of July 15, 1993; briefing paper re BOCES reform legislation capping salary and compensation for district superintendents
- Retirees Lobby Day, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  5/25, 6/1, 6/8, 6/15, 6/22 1994. List of state legislators from regional areas; tip sheet on effective lobbying; bullet points on retirement issues (pension COLA, health insurance); program for training session, including role-playing as legislators deflecting issues; letter to legislators from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson, summarizing issues; NYSUT press release, "Teachers to Lobby Weekly for Retiree Benefits"; list of participants; facilitative correspondence; letters from individual retirees to state legislators
- AFL-CIO AFT Meetings, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  February 1993. Facilitative correspondence
- Community College Luncheon Ft. Orange, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  February 1, 1993. List of attendees; letters of invitation to individual community college presidents from chair of NYSUT Community College Council; 1993-94 Executive Budget Highlights: SUNY and CUNY Community Colleges
- Ulster County Democratic Committee Phone Bank, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Telephone bank use agreement between NYSUT and Ulster County Democratic Committee; letter from NYSUT legislative director Ray Skuse to chair of Ulster County Democratic Committee requesting reimbursement for expenses
- End of Session Food Orders, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Menu; invoices
- Teacher Center Lobby Day, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  March 16, 1993. Agenda; catering invoices
- FNHP Ft. Orange Club, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  March 10, 1993. List of members of Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Committee; letter re lobbying day
- Committee of 100 Housing, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  2/22-23, 1993. Housing lists for lobbying day participants
- Higher Ed Lobby Day, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  March 1-2, 1993. Lists of participants; housing lists and other facilitative correspondence
- Community College Luncheon Ft. Orange Club, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  March 14, 1994. Letters of invitation to individual community college presidents; list of attendees
- Teacher Center Lobby Day, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  March 21, 1995. List of Teacher Centers located by districts of Ways and Means and Finance Committee members; correspondence re catering
- FNHP Lobby Day, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  March 14, 1995. Form letter inviting members of Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Committee to participate in lobbying day, with attached list of committee members and response form soliciting budget concerns; facilitative correspondence
- Committee of 100, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  3/6-7, 1995. List of committee members; expense vouchers and other facilitative correspondence
- Committee of 100, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  5/15-16, 1995. Tentative agenda; suggested order of issues briefing; schedule of appointments with members of Senate and Assembly higher education committees; list of participants; memos noting successes of previous lobby day, issues for upcoming visit
- Legislative Reception, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  January 30, 1995. Lists of invitees and attendees; letters of invitation to local leaders of community colleges; printed invitations; facilitative correspondence with caterer
- Political Action Committee (PAC) Meeting, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  October 27-28, 1995 Omni Hotel. Tentative agenda for Political Action Committee Conference; list of attendees; text of remarks by NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin; outline for workshop session; letters of appointment to members of Political Action Committee, with outline of responsibilities; facilitative correspondence
- PAC Housing, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  October 27-28, 1995. Housing response forms
- Dan Feldman Breakfast, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  November 9, 1995. Flyer invitation to Assembly member Dan Feldman reception; list of invitees; letters of invitation to labor leaders
- FEC (Federal Election Commission) Conference Alan Lewis, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  12/11-12, 1995. Invitation and program for Federal Election Commission conference on campaign finance laws for corporations and labor organizations; facilitative correspondence
- Retiree Training Best Western, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  4/25-26, 1994. Tentative agenda; list of attendees; letters to trainers
- Retiree Lobby Day, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  List of retiree lobby days scheduled for 1995; printing request forms for materials; briefing papers re supplemental pensions, retiree health insurance, multi-year tax cut proposal, tips on effective lobbying
- Retiree Training, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  Letters to volunteers re success of previous year's lobbying; schedule for upcoming lobby days by region; list of volunteers
- Budget End of Session Food Orders, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  Menus; facilitative correspondence
- Republican Senate, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  Sample telephone scripts on issues affecting education; lists of Republican state senators; related memos
- Community College Luncheon, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  November 10, 1995. List of attendees; list of community college presidents; letters of invitation
- Public Employee Conference (PEC) Breakfast, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  February 7, 1995. Printed invitation; letter to affiliates urging participation in annual legislative breakfast, noting need to show unity against threat of privatization
- TDA New York City Teachers' Retirement System, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  Travel documents
- New York State Festival, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Invitation from Gov. Pataki and NY congressional delegation to attend NYS Theatre Institute production of A Tale of Cinderella; NYS Festival fact sheet; list of donors to 1993 gift bag; related correspondence
- PEC Conference, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Sept. 17-20, 1995 Myrtle Beach. Agenda for NYS Public Employee Conference Annual Convention; convention call
- Higher Ed Lobby Day (folder 1), 1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  2/27-28, 1995. List of participants; facilitative correspondence
- Higher Education Lobby Day (folder 2), 1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  2/27-28, 1995. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Assembly and Senate; list of members of Senate and Assembly education and finance committees; briefing book, "Truth and Consequences-What the Executive Budget Doesn't Tell You about CUNY and SUNY!"; testimony of NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officials at legislative committee hearings; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators
- New York's Moynihan, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Press release from Moynihan Senate campaign, "Senator Moynihan and Organized Labor"; flyer with biographical information; campaign brochure; voting record on issues of importance to AFL-CIO
- New Local Presidents' Conference, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)